Guide to the Benjamin and Muriel Goldring Papers and Photographs TAM.374
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series V: Political Reference Files, 1939-2003
  - Irish Independence: Clippings, 1968-1980 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Israel-Palestine Conflict, 1947-1991 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Israel-Palestine Conflict: Clippings, 1975-1981 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Jewish Identity, The Holocaust and Israel undated, undated, 1962-1993 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Jewish Identity, The Holocaust and Israel: Clippings, 1974-1981 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - KKK, 1963-1980 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Lebanon, 1975-1982 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Legal Materials: General, Conferences, Announcements, etc., undated, 1961-1982 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Legal Notes, undated 1973-1974 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Loyalty Oaths, undated, 1954-1967 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Loyalty Oaths: Clippings, 1956-1968 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Miller, Arthur: Notes and Clippings on, 1966, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - NACCP and other African American Rights Organizations, 1964-1980 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - NAACP and other African American Rights Organizations: Clippings, 1966-1980 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Naturalization, undated, 1960-1975 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Nazi War Criminals, undated, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Nazi War Criminals: Clippings, 1968-1982 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Nuclear Energy/ The Atom, 1945-1981 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Oswald, Lee Harvey, 1963-1977 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Passport Revocation and Denial, 1939, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Passport Revocation and Denial: Clippings, 1958-1982 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Peace Movement, General, 1961-2001 (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Peace Movement, Women Strike for Peace, 1963-1982 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Police Misconduct, 1964-2003 (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Police in Politics, 1956-1980 (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Political Prisoners undated (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - Politics: Campaigns, 1944-1996 (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - Politics: Campaigns: Clippings, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - Politics: Fundraising, 1972-1998 (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - Politics: General, 1944-1982 (Box 14, Folder 35)
  - Politics: General: Clippings, 1972-1974 (Box 14, Folder 36)
  - Poverty, 1965-1970 (Box 14, Folder 37)
  - Poverty: Clippings, 1967-1976 (Box 14, Folder 38)
  - Prisoners Rights, undated, 1958-2000 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Prisoners Rights: Clippings, 1966-1981 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Prisoners Rights: Attica, undated, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Prisoners Rights: Attica: Clippings, 1970-1976 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Prisoners Rights: Martin Sostre, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Prisoners Rights: Martin Sostre: Clippings, 1970-1976 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Progressive Party, 1950-1954 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Property Law, Real Estate, 1967-1980 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Puerto Rico, undated, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Racism and Political Oppression, 1975-1979 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Russian War Relief (I), 1943-1946 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Russian War Relief (II), 1943-1946 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Russian War Relief: Publicity Material Guides (I), 1943-1946 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Russian War Relief: Publicity Material Guides (II), 1943-1946 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Sacco, Nicola and Bartolomeo Vanzetti, undated, 1959-1978 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Sacco, Nicola and Bartolomeo Vanzetti: Clippings, 1952-1978 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Schorr, Daniel, 1976-1977 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Science and Technology Workers Organizations, 1941-1961 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Scientists, Government Employment and Loyalty, 1945-1957 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Selective Service/ Draft Law, undated, 1966-1969 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Selective Service/ Draft Law: Clippings, 1966-1971 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Social Services, undated, 1942-1981 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Socialist Worker Party, undated, 1976-1982 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Socialist Worker Party: Clippings, undated, 1979-1981 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - South America, 1965-1997 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - South America: Clippings, 1966-1981 (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Southern Justice, 1951-1980 (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Southern Justice: Clippings, 1965-1979 (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Soviet Dissidents, 1978-1980 (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Soviet Dissidents: Clippings, 1970-1980 (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - Spain, 1969-1994 (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - Spain: Clippings, 1976-1984 (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - Spies: Clippings, 1967-1984 (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - Theft Protection, undated (Box 15, Folder 34)
  - Theft Protection: Clippings, undated (Box 15, Folder 35)
  - Thompson, Robert, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 36)
  - Union, General, 1944-1996 (Box 15, Folder 37)
  - Union, Local 19 Social Service Employees Union (SSEU), United Office and Professional Workers of America (UOPWA), 1946-1952 (Box 15, Folder 38)
  - U.S. Court of Appeals for the Second Circuit: Rules, 1954 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Vietnam, undated, 1965-1975 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Vietnam: Clippings, undated, 1965-1975 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Vietnam Veterans Against the War, undated, 1969-1975 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Vietnam Veterans Against the War: Clippings, undated, 1972-1973 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Watergate, 1973-1976 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Watergate: Clippings, 1972-1977 (Box 16, Folder 7)
- Series VI: Oversize Materials, 1900-1938
  This series contains certificates and diplomas of several Goldring and Goodman family members.
  - BG: Certificate Honoring Service in the International Brigade (In Spanish), 1938 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - BG and MG Parents and unidentified family member: Marriage Certificates (In Hebrew), 1909, 1916, undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Goodman, Abraham: Certificate of Naturalization, Aug 1, 1900 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Goodman, Max: Cornell University Transcript, 1912 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - MG: Erasmus High School Diploma, 1934 (Box 17, Folder 5)
- Series VII: Estate-Related Material, 2006-2007 (Box 18)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Repository permission is required for access. Please contact Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive, tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu, 212-998-2630.
  This series is mostly comprised of material relating to Muriel Goldring's illness, death and estate.
  - Correspondence Re: Estate, 2007 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Goldring Family Documents, undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Goodman Family Documents, undated (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - House: Sale for estate settlement, 2007 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Lease, 2006 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Meltzer, Martin: Attorney for Estate, 2007 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - (MG) Certificate of Cremation, 2007 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - (MG) Death Certificate, 2007 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - (MG) Power of Attorney, Health Care Proxy, etc., 2006 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - (MG) Time Line by Lillie Pope, 2007 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - (MG) Will, 2007 (Box 18, Folder 11)
- Series VIII: Photographs, 1905-2005
  Arrangement
  This series arranged mainly in chronological order, in two groups: Definitely dated materials, followed by undated materials for which dates have been guessed, the latter indicated by a question mark following the folder title dates. These chronologically-arranged materials are then followed by a small number of folders that are arranged alphabetically by folder name.
  Materials in this series are mainly photographs of the Goldrings' family and friends, and including images from every decade for a span of more than 100 years. They include both black and white and color images. Most were shot in the United States, but a few are from Europe, and there are some from Israel beginning in 1948. The earliest photographs appear to be mostly of Muriel Goodman Goldring's family. Most of the images from the 2000s document a memorial event held on June 4, 2000 to remember and honor Benjamin Goldring; guests at this event included at least one surviving member of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade. There are also two folders that contain images pertaining to Goldrings' political activities.
  - 1900s, 1905, 1907 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - 1910s, 1910, 1914-1916, 1919 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - 1920s, 1922-1924, 1928, 1929 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - 1930s, 1931, 1933, 1939 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - 1940s, 1941-1944, 1946, 1947, 1949 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - 1950s, 1951, 1952, 1954, 1956-1958 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - February 18, 1951 - Muriel and Benjamin Goldring Wedding - Proofs and Invitation (Box 19, Folder 6-a)
  - February 18, 1951 - Muriel and Benjamin Goldring Wedding Album (Box 19, Folder 6-b)
  - 1960s, 1960-1965, 1967-1969 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - 1970s, 1970-1974, 1976-1979 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - 1980s (1), 1980-1989 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - 1980s (2), 1988 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - 1990s, 1990, 1991, 1994, 1997-1999 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - 2000s, 2000, 2001, 2005 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - 1900s?, undated (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - 1910s?, undated (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - 1920s?, undated (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - 1930s?, undated (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - 1940s?, undated (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - 1950s?, undated (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - 1960s?, undated (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - 1970s?, undated (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - 1980s?, undated (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - 1990s?, undated (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - "The Caplan Family", 1965, 1969, ca. 1944 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Black and White Negatives (1), 1972, undated (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Black and White Negatives (2), undated (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Color Negatives and Slides, 1960, 1983, undated (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Undated (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Oversized Photographs, undated (Box Tamiment Shared OS005)
    Ben Goldring's paternal grandparents; unidentified woman portrait (late 19th century?), unidentified man portrait, portrait of Ben Goldring as a boy (1910s), photo collage (ca. 1990s)
  - Political, 1938, 1966, 1976, 1977, 1986, undated (Box 21, Folder 4)
    Images in this folder mainly concern the Rosenberg and Sobel cases, and gatherings of the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB), and two images from the Spanish Civil War of recuperating wounded soldiers from the International Brigades.
  - Political - "Morton Sobell Talk" "Photos Removed for Exhibit 6/09", 1983, ca. 1953 (Box 21, Folder 5)
- Series IX: Audio Materials, 1953, 1980
  - Audiocassette Tape: "July 20, 1980 Herman Badillo, Roy Cohn, Muriel Goldring WPIX Channel 11; July 27, 1980 Sunday, Roy Cohn, BG, Herman Badillo, FOIA law student. Channel 11 WPIX 10 am ...25 min.", cuid13387 (Box 22, Folder 1, E-records tamwag_TAM374, E-records cuid13387)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 54 min
  - Phonograph Records (45s) and Lyrics for "Thirty Years - A Prison Ballad", ca 1953 (Box 22, Folder 2)
- Series X: Ephemera and Artifacts, 1912, 1963-1989, undated
  - Advertisement for Movie, "Salt of the Earth", circa 1954 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Irish Northern Aid and Death Penalty Stickers and Bumper Sticker, undated (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Program for Cornell University Class Day, 1912 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Sadie Goodman and Muriel Goldring's Brighton Beach (Brooklyn, New York) Bath and Raquet Club Membership/Photo Identification Cards, 1963, 1979, 1983-1986, 1989 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Trading Stamps and Postal Stamps, undated (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Unidentified Children's Drawings, undated (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - War Bond Pledge Certificate of Recognition for Emily Sigal, circa 1944 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Poster Published (for Fund Appeal) by Russian War Relief, Inc.: "38,000,000 Escaped -- 10,000,000 Died", circa 1942 (Flat-file-folder 5)
  - Silhouette ca. 19th century (and oval photograph under which it was found), undated (Box Tamiment Shared OS005)
  - Small Plaque (possibly a swimming award), undated (Box Tamiment Shared OS005)